[
    {
       "question": "'Valid', 'Same', 'Full' are types of ... in a Neural Network",
       "options": ["pooling", "padding"],
       "correct_answer": "padding"
     },
     {
      "question": "Padding in Neural Network is widely used in .... processing",
      "options": ["image", "natural language"],
      "correct_answer": "image"
    },
    {
      "question": "<strong>Convolution Operation</strong> in CNN involves sliding the filters over ...",
      "options": ["the output data, element-wise multiplying the filter values with the overlapping input values, and summing the results", "the input data, element-wise multiplying the filter values with the overlapping input values, and summing the results"],
      "correct_answer": "the input data, element-wise multiplying the filter values with the overlapping input values, and summing the results"
    },
    {
      "question": "RNN / Transformers: Padding is used in Tokenization in NLP for which purpose?",
      "options": ["for randomization of sequences", "it adds special tokens (often representing padding) to ensure that all sequences in a batch have the same length"],
      "correct_answer": "it adds special tokens (often representing padding) to ensure that all sequences in a batch have the same length"
    },
    {
      "question": "'Valid' type of Padding means",
      "options": ["no padding is added, and the filter or pooling window moves across the input without extra elements", "padding is added, and the filter or pooling window moves across the input with one extra element"],
      "correct_answer": "no padding is added, and the filter or pooling window moves across the input without extra elements"
    },
    {
      "question": "<strong>Output size = (Input size + 2 * padding - filter size) / stride + 1</strong><br> illustrates  what type of <strong>Padding</strong> in CNN?",
      "options": ["Full", "Valid", "Same"],
      "correct_answer": "Same"
    },
    {
      "question": "In 2023, in NN context, how many spatial dimensions are used in NN?",
      "options": ["1D, 2D, 3D", "1D, 2D, 3D, 4D", "1D, 2D, 3D, 4D, 5D"],
      "correct_answer": "1D, 2D, 3D"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of device-agnostic code?",
      "options": ["the purpose is to create a software that stably works on the same device and does not depend on OS of device", "the purpose is to create software that provides a seamless and consistent experience to users regardless of the specific device they are using"],
      "correct_answer": "the purpose is to create software that provides a seamless and consistent experience to users regardless of the specific device they are using"
    },
    {
      "question": "Explain this line of code<br>y_pred = torch.round(torch.sigmoid(y_logits))<br>",
      "options": ["activation function (sigmoid in this case) is applied to y_logits (a tensor), the output is rounded to the nearest integer, since sigmoid function produces values 0 or 1", "activation function (sigmoid in this case) is applied to y_logits (a tensor), the output is rounded to the nearest float, since sigmoid function produces values between 0 and 1"],
      "correct_answer": "activation function (sigmoid in this case) is applied to y_logits (a tensor), the output is rounded to the nearest integer, since sigmoid function produces values 0 or 1"
    },
    {
      "question": "A = torch.arange(-10, 10, 1) and B = torch.arange(-10, 10, 0.1) creates tensors of which types?",
      "options": ["A is int64, B is float32, because of steps = 1 and 0.1 respectively", "these are not tensors, these are one dimensional arrays"],
      "correct_answer": "A is int64, B is float32, because of steps = 1 and 0.1 respectively"
    },
    {
      "question": "A = torch.arange(-10, 10, 1, dtype = torch.float32), in this code float32 tensor type is forcedly set",
      "options": ["Yes", "No"],
      "correct_answer": "Yes"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does this construction mean (generally in Python)?<br>def relu(x: torch.Tensor) -> torch.Tensor:...<br>",
      "options": ["this function accepts x of torch.Tensor type and returns torch.Tensor type as output", "this construction does not work, because the function already knows the output type, it is torch.Tensor"],
      "correct_answer": "this function accepts x of torch.Tensor type and returns torch.Tensor type as output"
    },
    {
      "question": "... refer to a group of data points that share similar characteristics or form a distinct pattern within a dataset",
      "options": ["Blob", "Cluster", "All the above"],
      "correct_answer": "All the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "PCA, tSNE, NMF are algorithms of ...",
      "options": ["dimensionality reduction in unsupervised learning", "clustering in unsupervised learning", "dimensionality reduction in supervised learning"],
      "correct_answer": "dimensionality reduction in unsupervised learning"
    },
    {
      "question": "CNN, RNN belong to",
      "options": ["supervised deep learning", "supervised machine learning", "clustering in unsupervised learning"],
      "correct_answer": "supervised deep learning"
    },
    {
      "question": "As a Machine Learning Engineer you would like to help your QA colleagues to predict number of defects in upcoming Release.<br>Looking into data being collected, you see there is a number of features that looks like have non-linear relationship to number of defects.<br>What (from the given options below) would you choose?",
      "options": ["Ensamble Methods, Neural Networks", "Multiple Linear Regression, Logistic Regression"],
      "correct_answer": "Ensamble Methods, Neural Networks"
    },
    {
      "question": "Being a ML engineer you would like to help your QA colleagues and generate <strong>Test Cases</strong> for the next release (yes, it is a very complex task, but let us assume it comes to a model choice only), what would you choose from the list below?",
      "options": ["sequence-to-sequence models (Seq2Seq)", "CNN", "Both can be used, but Seq2Seq is 'natural' and therefore faster"],
      "correct_answer": "Both can be used, but Seq2Seq is more 'natural' and therefore faster"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does require Machine Learning from the list below?",
      "options": ["Fibonacci Sequence Prediction", "sorting a large list of numbers (1 000 000 + items)", "email spam classification"],
      "correct_answer": "email spam classification"
    },
    {
      "question": "Validating the strength of a password requires machine learning to analyze patterns and complexity, why?",
      "options": ["it does not, because validation is rule-based", "it does, because I am not developer / ML engineer and to me this validation seems magic"],
      "correct_answer": "it does not, because validation is rule-based"
    },
    {
      "question": "Accuracy Evaluation Metric vs Imbalanced Classes",
      "options": ["not the best choice for sure", "why not"],
      "correct_answer": "not the best choice for sure"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the context of imbalanced datasets, precision and recall are often considered more informative metrics than accuracy",
      "options": ["Yes", "No"],
      "correct_answer": "Yes"
    },
    {
      "question": "... = True Positives / (True Positives + False Positives) * 100",
      "options": ["Precision", "Recall"],
      "correct_answer": "Precision"
    },
    {
      "question": ".. = True Positives / (True Positives + False Negatives) * 100",
      "options": ["Recall", "Accuracy"],
      "correct_answer": "Recall"
    },
    {
      "question": "In Pytorch, there torchmetrics.Accuracy(), torchmetrics.Recall() and torchmetrics.Precision() do all the evaluation job",
      "options": ["Thanks God!", "No, you have to calculate manually"],
      "correct_answer": "Thanks God!"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does Computer Vision involve in context of Data Science?",
      "options": ["it involves design & development of new hardware concept that supports processing of large volumes of data", "it involves the development of algorithms, models, and systems that can interpret and make decisions based on visual data, such as images and videos"],
      "correct_answer": "it involves the development of algorithms, models, and systems that can interpret and make decisions based on visual data, such as images and videos"
    },
    {
      "question": "In context of Computer Vision this is called: following the movement and interactions of objects over a sequence of frames in a video",
      "options": ["Object Tracking and Detection", "Movement Recognition Tracking and Detection"],
      "correct_answer": "Object Tracking and Detection"
    },
    {
      "question": "Matrices play a central role in representing and solving systems of linear equations",
      "options": ["Yes", "No"],
      "correct_answer": "Yes"
    },
    {
      "question": "Matrix A = [1 2, 3 4] is",
      "options": ["square Matrix", "rectengular Matrix"],
      "correct_answer": "square Matrix"
    },
    {
      "question": "Matrix B = [2] is it a valid matrix?",
      "options": ["Yes", "No"],
      "correct_answer": "Yes"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is identity matrix in Linear Algebra?",
      "options": ["a square diagonal matrix, with all entries on the main diagonal equal to 0, and the rest 1", "a square diagonal matrix, with all entries on the main diagonal equal to 1, and the rest 0"],
      "correct_answer": "a square diagonal matrix, with all entries on the main diagonal equal to 1, and the rest 0"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is binary matrix?",
      "options": ["a matrix whose entries are all either 0 or 1", "a matrix whose entries are all either X or Y"],
      "correct_answer": "a matrix whose entries are all either 0 or 1"
    },
    {
      "question": "Boolean Matrix is",
      "options": ["the same as identity matrix", "matrix that contain 0 or 1 and is the same as binary matrix"],
      "correct_answer": "matrix that contain 0 or 1 and is the same as binary matrix"
    },
    {
      "question": "",
      "options": ["", ""],
      "correct_answer": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "",
      "options": ["", ""],
      "correct_answer": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "",
      "options": ["", ""],
      "correct_answer": ""
    }
     
     
   
   ]
   